<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../xsl/page.xsl"?>

<page menu="teaching">
	<title>Adam Koprowski :: Proving with computer assistance</title>
	<content>
	<heading>Proving with Computer Assistance: practical part (2IF48)</heading>

		<P>This is the page of the practical part of the course <I>Proving with Computer Assistance</I>.
		For the information about the theoretical part of the course please consult the web page for 
		<A href="http://www.win.tue.nl/~wsinrpn/courses-2if40.htm">2IF40</A>.
		</P>

	<subheading>Teachers:</subheading>
		<UL>
			<LI><A href="http://www.win.tue.nl/~fdechesn">F. Dechesne</A> (lectures, final assignment)</LI>
			<LI><A href="http://adam-koprowski.net">A. Koprowski</A> (lab sessions, final assignment)</LI>
		</UL>

	<heading>News/announcements</heading> 
		<UL>
			<LI><B>8/06: The ultimate deadline for handing in solutions to the final assingment is set to 15/07.</B></LI>
			<LI>24/04: Updated hints on performing <A href="#hints">case distinction</A>.</LI>
			<LI>13/04: Some hints <A href="#hints">published</A>.</LI>
			<LI>29/03: Materials from the last lecture available in <A href="#materials">materials</A> section.</LI>
			<LI>28/03: Announced <A href="#hours">office hours</A> for the consultation for the final assignment.</LI>
			<LI>28/03: Registration finished. If you did not receive email confirming your registration for the final assignment 
				please contact <A href="http://adam-koprowski.net">me</A> as soon as possible!</LI>
			<LI>5/03: Details about the final assignment are <A href="#finassgn">available now.</A></LI>
			<LI>27/02: The problems with CoqIDE in version 8.1 of Coq are resolved by now and hence we decided to use this
	    		version of the system for the course (see the updated <A href="#instinstr">installation instructions</A>)</LI>
			<LI>26/02: Exercises for lab session with Coq are now <A href="#materials">available</A>.</LI>
			<LI>14/02: Materials from the first lecture (handout version of slides + Coq script) are now <A href="#materials">available</A>.</LI>
			<LI>14/02: Posted <A href="#instinstr">installation instructions</A> for Coq + CoqIDE.</LI>
			<LI>Registration for lab session is required. You can register during the lecture on Wed 14/02, 10:45-12:30, Matrix 1.41. 
	    		Following options are available:
				<UL>
					<LI>Wed 28 Feb., 10:45-12:30, MA 1.41 <B>(group full!)</B></LI>
					<LI>Wed 28 Feb., 15:30-17:15, HG 5.95</LI>
					<LI>Thu 1 Mar, 13:30-15:15, HG 5.95</LI>
				</UL>
			</LI>
			<LI>More to come... check this page out later to find all the information about the practical part of the course.</LI>
		</UL>

	<heading>Coq v 8.1 resources</heading>

	<subheading>Installation</subheading>

		Installation required before the practical session! See <A href="#instinstr">below</A> for installation instructions.
		<UL>
	  		<LI>homepage: <A href="http://coq.inria.fr">http://coq.inria.fr</A></LI>
  			<LI>download page: <A href="http://coq.inria.fr/distrib-eng.html">http://coq.inria.fr/distrib-eng.html</A></LI>	   
  			<LI>To comfortably work with <EM>Coq</EM> you will also need an user interface (see below)</LI>
		</UL>

	<subheading>Interface</subheading>

		Working with Coq requires an user interface. Basically there are two choices:
		<UL>
  			<LI><B>CoqIDE</B> (<A href="http://coq.inria.fr/distrib-eng.html">Download</A>) is a user-friendly <EM>Coq</EM> user interface. 
      			Its main disadvantage is that the version for Windows is <u>very unstable</u>. </LI>
  			<LI><B>Proof General</B> (<A href="http://proofgeneral.inf.ed.ac.uk">Homepage</A> | <A href="http://proofgeneral.inf.ed.ac.uk/download">Download</A>)
          		is a <EM>Coq</EM> user interface working on top of <A href="http://www.xemacs.org/">XEmacs</A>. It is not as user 
		  		friendly as <EM>CoqIDE</EM> (unless you are familiar with <EM>XEmacs</EM>) but is stable even on Windows. Besides it 
		  		also works with other proof assistants, like <A href="http://www.cl.cam.ac.uk/Research/HVG/Isabelle/">Isabelle</A>.</LI>
		</UL>

	<subheading>Materials</subheading>

		<UL>
  			<LI><A href="http://www.cs.chalmers.se/Cs/Research/Logic/TypesSS05/Extra/bertot_coq.pdf">Coq in a Hurry (pdf)</A>:
	            a nice quick introduction to <EM>Coq</EM> (recommended).</LI>
  			<LI><A href="http://coq.inria.fr/V8.1/refman/index.html">Online reference manual (html)</A>: useful if you need more 
	            information on certain aspect of <EM>Coq</EM> (like usage of a particular tactic etc.)</LI>
  			<LI><A href="http://coq.inria.fr/library">Online library</A>: browsable standard library of <EM>Coq</EM>
	            (with index to all the lemmas and definitions)</LI>			
		</UL>

	<subheading>Installation instructions</subheading>
	<A name="instinstr"></A>

		<P>The following instructions assume you are using Windows operating system. If you are interested in installation
		for another platform then consult <A href="http://coq.inria.fr/distrib-eng.html">Coq distribution</A> page or
		contact the course instructor.</P>

		<P>For the purpose of this course we will be using the interface of CoqIDE as its installation is very easy. 
		It boils down to downloading the Coq 8.0pl3 distribution from 
		<A href="ftp://ftp.inria.fr/INRIA/coq/V8.0pl3/coq-8.0pl3-win.exe">here</A> and following the installation 
		instructions (basically pressing next a number of times). At this point you may want to upgrade to 
		Coq 8.1 which you can do by installing its distribution from <A href="ftp://ftp.inria.fr/INRIA/coq/V8.1/coq-8.1-win.exe">
		here</A>. This has the following advantages:</P>
		<UL>
 			<LI><A href="http://coq.inria.fr/doc-eng.html">documentation</A> and the 
     			<A href="http://coq.inria.fr/library-eng.html">description of the standard library</A> 
 				on Coq web page refer to ver. 8.1 of the system and there are some changes compared with 8.0pl3 and</LI>
 			<LI>CoqIDE seems to be more stable in 8.1</LI>
		</UL>

	<heading>Course schedule and materials</heading>
	<A name="materials"></A>

		<TABLE class="showTable">
		<TR>
			<TH>Time &amp; Location</TH>
			<TH>Title</TH>
			<TH>Materials</TH>
		</TR>
		<TR>
			<TD>14 Feb, 10:45-12:30, MA 1.41</TD>
			<TD>Introduction to Coq</TD>
			<TD><A href="teaching/pca-06-07/lecture1.pdf">slides</A> &amp; <A href="teaching/pca-06-07/demo07.v">Coq demo script</A></TD>
		</TR>
		<TR>
			<TD>
				28 Feb, 10:45-12:30, MA 1.41<BR/>
				28 Feb, 15:30-17:15, HG 5.95<BR/>
	 			1 Mar, 13:30-15:15, HG 5.95
			</TD>
			<TD>Lab sessions: hands-on experience with Coq</TD>
			<TD><A href="teaching/pca-06-07/CoqLab07.v">Coq exercises</A></TD>
		</TR>
		<TR>
			<TD>7 Mar, 10:45-12:30, MA 1.41</TD>
			<TD>More information about Coq. <BR/> Short introduction to PVS
			</TD>
		<TD>
			<A href="teaching/pca-06-07/lecture2.pdf">slides</A> &amp; 
			<A href="http://www.cs.ru.nl/~erikpoll/Teaching/PVS/index.html">PVS demo script</A><SUP>*</SUP><BR/><SUP>*</SUP><I>available via web-page of <A href="http://www.cs.ru.nl/~erikpoll">Erik Poll</A></I>
		</TD>
		</TR>
		</TABLE>

	<heading>Final assignment</heading>
	<A name="finassgn"></A>

	<subheading>Procedure:</subheading>

		For the final assignment follow those steps:
		<UL>
	  		<LI>Form a team of 2 or 3 students.</LI>
  			<LI>Choose the exercise from the following list of exercises:
      			<A href="teaching/pca-06-07/assignments07.pdf">assignments07.pdf</A>.<BR/>
      			Here is the Coq script for exercise D: <A href="teaching/pca-06-07/STLC.v">STLC.v</A>
  			</LI>
  			<LI>Register for the final assignment <SPAN class="warning">before March 15th</SPAN> by sending an email 
      		to <A href="http://adam-koprowski.net">A. Koprowski</A>. The email should 
	  		contain names <B>and</B> student numbers of all the members of the group <B>and</B> 
	  		your choice of the exercise.
  		</LI>
  		<LI>Solve the exercise and write a report (more on that below).</LI>
  		<LI>Send your solution (Coq file + report) <SPAN class="warning">before May 11th</SPAN> to your
      		assignor (<A href="http://www.win.tue.nl/~fdechesn">F. Dechesne</A> or
      		<A href="http://adam-koprowski.net">A. Koprowski</A>)
	  		<B>The last chance deadline: <SPAN class="warning">July 15th</SPAN></B>
  		</LI>
  		<LI>After submitting your solution make an appointment for the final evaluation. 
      		Final evaluation is a short meeting (30min) of all the members of the group 
	  		with their assignor where you will shortly discuss your solution (both Coq 
	  		part and the report). You will also receive your grade then.</LI>
		</UL>

	<subheading>Report</subheading>

		A couple of remarks considering the requirements for the report:
		<UL>
  		<LI>Do not make it too long. 15 pages is the absolute maximum but normally it
      		should be much shorter. Keep in mind that longer does not mean better!</LI>
  		<LI>What you should write:
    		<UL>
	  			<LI>Names and student numbers of all the members of the group.</LI>
	  			<LI>Explanation of the problem and your approach to it.</LI>
	  			<LI>Description of the main problems you encountered and solutions you used.
		      		If you had some alternative ideas to solve those problems describe them
		  			and explain your choice for the solution to this problem.</LI>
	  			<LI>Write about your experience with the prover. What did you like, what you 
	      			did not like etc.</LI>
	  			<LI>Describe the cooperation within the group and the division of labor.</LI>
	  			<LI>Add the Coq code as an appendix.</LI>
 			</UL>
  		</LI>
  		<LI>What you should <B>not</B> write
    		<UL>
	  			<LI>Do not unnecessarily repeat the code. Refer to appendix and quote the
	      			code only to illustrate something.</LI>
  	  			<LI>Do not write obvious things! Description of the proofs of the shape:
	      			<I>"the goal is as follows so we apply this tactic and that is what we
		  			get..."</I> are useless. </LI>
			</UL>
  		</LI>
	</UL>

	<subheading>Office hours for the final assignment</subheading>
	<A name="hours"></A>

		Should you have any questions concerning the final assignment you can can contact your
		supervisor during the office hours: 
		<UL>
	  		<LI>groups supervised by Francien Dechesne: 4/04-25/04, Tuesdays and Wednesdays 12:45-14:00, HG 7.17</LI>
  			<LI>groups supervised by Adam Koprowski: 11/04-4/05, Wednesdays 13:00-15:00 + arbitrary other time upon appointment, HG 6.78</LI>
		</UL>

	<subheading>Tips &amp; tricks</subheading>
	<A name="hints"></A>

		<UL>
			<LI>Avoid using the type bool; define predicates using Prop. Don't use equality (=) to prove 
		    	equivalence of propositions, use bi-implication (<pre>&lt;-&gt;</pre>) instead.
			</LI>
			<LI>For a way of doing case distinction see the following <A href="teaching/pca-06-07/Cases.v">script</A></LI>
			<LI>If you have contradictory hypotheses then you may want to convert your goal to '<I>False</I>'.
		    	This can be done by '<I>apply False_ind.</I>' (try: '<I>Check False_Ind.</I>')</LI>
		</UL>
		
	</content>
</page>
