<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../xsl/page.xsl"?>

<page menu="teaching">
	<title>Adam Koprowski :: Coq and rewriting</title>
	<content>
		<heading>What</heading>
		<EM>Coq and rewriting</EM>: a series of 3 lectures/lab sessions given as part of the advanced track of the 
		<A href="http://www.phil.uu.nl/isr2010/">5th International School on Rewriting (ISR '10)</A> in Utrecht, Netherlands.
		
		<heading>Abstract</heading>
		<P>
			<EM>Coq</EM> is an interactive theorem prover. On the one hand it allows to express mathematical theorems and mechanically 
			check correctness of their proofs. On the other hand it encompasses a functional programming language, allowing to write 
			programs within the system and reason about their correctness, hence providing a software verification platform. This course 
			will:
			<UL>
				<LI>introduce Coq as a tool;</LI>
				<LI>present recent work in the term rewriting community on using theorem proving technology to certify termination proofs 
					for term rewriting systems; and	</LI>
				<LI>include lab sessions, where students will be presented with a number of exercises, giving them an opportunity to have 
					a hands-on experience with the system.</LI>
			</UL>
		</P>

		<heading>Coq installation</heading>
		<P>
		  <SPAN class="warning">WARNING!</SPAN>
		  All students taking part in this course are expected to have a working version of Coq pre-installed
		  when joining the course. Please follow the instructions below and in case of any problems contact <A href="http://adam-koprowski.net">me</A>.
		</P>

		<P>
		  What you will need to take part in this course is:
		  <UL>
		    <LI><EM>Coq 8.2pl1</EM> -- you can download it <A href="http://coq.inria.fr/download">here</A>. If you are running Linux (preferred platform
		      for Coq developments) you may need to install it from sources. For more information see: 
		      <A href="http://www.chargueraud.org/arthur/projects/proofs/install/">Coq installation tutorial</A> (courtesy of Arthur Charguéraud).
		    </LI>
		    <LI>An interface to Coq: i.e. either <EM>ProofGeneral</EM> (preferred) or <EM>CoqIDE</EM>. CoqIDE comes bundled with standard Coq distribution.
		      For ProofGeneral you will need to have (X)emacs on your system and then follow instructions from: 
		      <A href="http://proofgeneral.inf.ed.ac.uk/download">Proof General's download page</A>.
		    </LI>
		    <LI><SPAN class="warning">Please do this installation well in advance of the course</SPAN>, so that I will be able to assist you in case 
		      you run into any problems. There will be no time during the course to do that!</LI>
		  </UL>
		</P>

		<heading>Materials</heading>
		<div class="download">
			Exercises:
			<A href="teaching/isr-10/Day1_CoqIntro_ex.v">Day1</A>
			<A href="teaching/isr-10/Day2_AbsSN_ex.v">Day2</A>
			<A href="teaching/isr-10/Day3_StringRev_ex.v">Day3</A>
		</div>		
		<div class="download">
			Slides:
			<A href="teaching/isr-10/slides-handout.pdf">handout [PDF]</A>
			<A href="teaching/isr-10/slides-presentation.pdf">presentation [PDF]</A>
		</div>		
	</content>
</page>
